# Joshua Jainga

Phone: 253.347.8441 Email: jjainga@gmail.com Personal Portfolio: <a href="https://portfile.herokuapp.com/">https://portfile.herokuapp.com/</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://github.com/in/joshuajainga">www.linkedin.com/in/joshuajainga</a> Github: <a href="https://github.com/jiainga">https://github.com/jiainga</a>

#### **Brand Statement**

Full Stack Developer leveraging economics and operations management background to help solve complex problems to improve user experience. Completing a full stack development program through the University of Washington with newly developed skills in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB and self-taught in Python. Quick to learn, integrate and teach new knowledge to benefit the team I am supporting. I am excited to continue to grow my skills to build a better experience for everyone.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Programming Language:** HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, React iQuery, Python, VBA

**Soft Skills:** adaptable, time management, innovative, collaborative

## **Projects**

**Covid-19 Resource page:** Collaborated with a team to create a Covid-19 resource app using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and utilized Microsoft's Bing Covid-19 data API. The application lets users see real time changes in Covid statistics and look up the closest Covid-19 testing centers.

https://jjainga.github.io/Covid-19-Resource-Page/

**Personify:** Create the schema and backend routes for the application Personify using MySql, Javascript and Sequelize. This application allows users to take a quiz to find out what their personality archetype.

https://personify-personality-quiz.herokuapp.com/

#### **Education**

# **UW Coding Bootcamp**

August 2020 - Current

University of Washington

### **Bachelor of Science in Economics**

September 2012 - June 2015

Eastern Washington University, Cheney, WA

Minor in Decision Science

Honors Recognition - International Economic Society

Study Abroad - Global City Hong Kong

# **Professional Experience**

# **Fulfillment Center Operations Area Manager II**

February 2019 - Current

Amazon BFI4, Kent, WA

- Assist in the development of new area managers/process assistants in the outbound department. Leads department meetings amongst peers to discuss weekly changes and metrics
- Creates learning curve performance calculator with VBA to identify areas of opportunity per associate in the chuting/pack department by showing percent to labor plan, week-over-week performance, trend for current shift. information is used to help with targeting performance coaching for department managers.
- Creates hourly shift tracker with VBA to assist in the ad hoc reporting of all outbound department's metrics. Information is used to identify opportunities in current labor plan and show relative performance in day-over-day and week-over-week.
- Leading 30-60 people to deliver 200,000 units daily at 95-105% to labor plan.
- Create purchase order requisitions for materials to better associates work life.
- Safety Leadership Index of 6% unfavorable against the network average of 13% unfavorable.
- Track quarterly shift metrics to proactively identify areas of opportunity to meet volume and through-put-hour shift goals.
- Cross-functional collaboration to ensure customer's order deadlines and critical pool times are met.
- Create ad hoc reporting tools to identify productivity opportunities (performance levels of 80% or below) to drive proactive coaching. Daily coaching to individuals drive 5-10% increase in performance.
- Determine team productivity needs and work with other Area Managers to balance shift labor needs.
- Develop Associates to assist in their promotional and career goals.
- Assure that Associate compliance and consistency is maintained, and that corrective action is taken when needed.

#### **Seasonal Procurement Operations Analyst**

August 2018 – February 2019

Amazon BFI4, Kent, WA

- Create reports analyzing trends of spending per blanket purchase order to evaluate potential cost savings and present to Sr. Ops.
- Initiate and lead cost saving project in collaboration with Sr. Ops and finance team, which saves \$120K annually.
- Take part in discussions with Sr. Ops on barriers for Associates and provide support with solutions. Build and manage vendor relationships, negotiate/facilitate vendor proposal for site projects.

Deep Dive in data of vendor spending history to determine future budgets.

Approve Coupa web requests with a 24-hour deadline.

Track account payable holds to find the root cause of issues and execute resolutions.

- Resolve a standard of 80% account payable holds on a weekly basis (six weeks of 100% resolution).
- Facilitate communication between supporting vendors and Amazon to provide a safe, clean, and efficient work facility.

# **Non-Inventory Receiver**

May 2018- August 2018

Amazon BFI4, Kent, WA

- Develop an unloading process which increases productivity by 20% per unload, resulting in the potential for an additional 365 unloads per year.
- Create pivot tables to view consumption of slow-moving items to better plan storage areas.
- Perform and record daily counts to track non-inventory materials to meet building needs.
  Receive and verify purchases through Coupa and disperse non-inventory items to appropriate departments.
- Maintain consistent workflow throughout the building by prioritizing standard work against the needs of other departments.
  Certified in power industrial trucks, vertical reciprocating conveyor, and trailer dock and release.

#### **Process Guide, Sort Amazon Fulfillment Engine (Amazon Fulfillment Engine)**

November 2017- May 2018

Amazon BFI4, Kent, WA

- Personal performance rating of 145% to labor plan for a six-week average, resulting in 108 hours gained back to the building. Assist in managing Associates to balance the staffing of all positions within the sorting process of AFE.
- Demonstrate strong work ethic and leadership for other Associates.
- Identify and solve problems with the sorting process to ensure the highest quality possible; kept defects below 1%.
- Training experience in all positions within AFE (induct, rebin, pack).